<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Surrey Hills Cycle Hire</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Surrey Hills Cycle Hire</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 14:04:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Route Added - Route 4 Thursley, Witley and Busses Commons</title>
      <link>/post/new-route-added/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 14:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-route-added/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re blessed by having access to large amounts of Common land close by. This route takes in Thursley, Elstead, Ockley, Witley, Mare Hill and Busses Commons.
It&amp;rsquo;s a common misconception that Common Land has no ownership, in fact it is owned by either individuals, groups of individuals or organisations. In the case of these commons, it&amp;rsquo;s a mixture. Thursley Common is owned by Natural England, Elstead and Ockley Commons are owned by the Ministry of Defence, Witley Common is owned by The National Trust, Mare Hill Common is owned by Waverley District Council and Busses Common is owned by Hambledon&amp;rsquo;s Lord of The Manor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much does it cost to charge an Electric Mountain Bike?</title>
      <link>/post/cost-of-charging-an-ebike-battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 14:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cost-of-charging-an-ebike-battery/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we&amp;rsquo;ll take advantage of a coffee stop to top up the bike battery on a mountain bike. If it&amp;rsquo;s been a long day with lots of climbing and the rider has been seduced by turbo mode, then a bit of extra juice to get home is nice insurance. We&amp;rsquo;ll always ask for permission to plug in and, understandably, are often asked what effect we&amp;rsquo;ll have on the establishments electricity bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why 1x11 Mountain Bikes?</title>
      <link>/post/why1x11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why1x11/</guid>
      <description>Our Voodoo Bizango hard-tail mountain bikes have what&amp;rsquo;s known as a 1x11 drive train. What this means, simply, is that they have just one chain ring at the front and a cassette with 11 cogs on the rear wheel. Just 11 gears doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound much, but in the world of gears, more isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily better.
The first mountain bikes, &amp;ldquo;Klunkerz&amp;rdquo;, had just one gear. But over time more gears were added, first at the back and then with the addition of up to three chainrings on the front.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>